Guide to the Donald Jay Grout papers,1929-2002.
Grout, Donald Jay papers
- Series IV. The Operas of Alessandro Scarlatti
  - The Operas of Alessandro Scarlatti
    - Scarlatti: Grout's letters to Libby, Hardee; re: Scarlatti editions, 1972-1980 (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - Honors at Cornell and British Academy, 1978 (Box 57, Folder 14)
    - Scarlatti: A. Scarlatti - paperback/Norton "Italian Baroque Masters", 1983-1984 (Box 57, Folder 15)
    - Scarlatti: Grout letters - Scarlatti editions, 1970-1979 (Box 57, Folder 16)
    - Scarlatti: correspondence - Hanley, 1967-1974 (Box 57, Folder 17)
- Series V. Reviews, articles, lectures, and papers, cxvzxcv
  - Early Romantic Music and Opera, Texas, 1944 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - The University and the Art of Music, Columbia, 1954 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Is Music a Universal Language?, Sweet Briar, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - The Irrational in 19th Century Music, Baltimore, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Chorus in Early Opera, Royal College of Music, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Verdi's Aida, Cornell, 1962 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Structure and Style in St. Matthew Passion, Wooster, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Spontaneity and Adaptation in the History of Music, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Oliver Strunk Festschrift, Written 1965, Published 1968 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Strunkschrift outline and notes, 1965 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Music and History, Phi Beta Kappa, 1965 (1972 - 1973) (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - College Music Association - transcript of remarks, New Orleans, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Friedrich Blume, Die evangelische Kirchenmusik, review of second edition, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Symbol and Sound in Music, Portugal, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Music History and Musical Reality, 1966 - 1972 (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Fidelio, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Kinkeldey, Necrology, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Music 481, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - Review of Oxford History of Music, Vol. IV, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - Early 19th Century Music (Music 681), 1968 (Box 24, Folder 32)
  - Notes - Rolland's Histoire de l'opera en Europe, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 33)
  - St. John's Passion, program notes, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 34)
  - Editing Early Italian Opera, with some notes on Scarlatti's Eraclea (essay for Miss Reynolds), 1969 (Box 24, Folder 35)
  - Mozart in the History of Opera, 1968 - 1970 (Box 24, Folder 36)
  - Some Aspects of American Music from the beginning to 1915, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 37)
  - Programs, broadsides, and notices (Box 24, Folder 38)
  - Grove-MacMillan, in relation to the 6th edition of Grove's Dictionary of Music and Musicians, 1969 - 1975 (Box 25, Folder 1-4)
  - Handel and the Opera Seria review, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Music 681-682 (musicology seminar), 1963 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Don Giovanni, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Don Giovanni, Williams College, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Graham Hardie, thesis, 1971 - 1972 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Kirkendale: Antonio Caldara: La Vita, review for AMS, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Opera in the 20th Century, London, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Performance in the Classical Period by Edward S. Derr, 1974, AMS annual meeting, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Corelli e Stradella from C. Gianturco, circa late 1975 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Symposium paper, Berlin, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Peabody Conservatory, Elliot Galkin (also, Baltimore Symphony Orchestra), 1977 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Alessandro Scarlatti and the dramma per musica, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Notes: Voyage Musical autour des Pays-Bas (tour of dutch organs), 1960 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous notes and articles, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous notes and articles, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Mss. scores Aiace - atto primo by Gasparini (transcription), n.d. (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Mss. scores Aiace - atto secondo by Gasparini (transcription), n.d. (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Mss. scores Aiace - atto terzo by Gasparini (seminar transcription), 1966 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Bibliography cards, n.d. (Box 46)
  - mss. music, Vienna 1951 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - La Messe de Nostre Dame and other mss. music, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Music 301 Examination, 1949, 1951 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Mss. music notebook, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Music 229 music mss., n.d. (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Music 301 music mss., 27 January, 1954 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - La Musica di Andrea Della Corte, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Music 33 The Opéra-Comique pages 1-97 (unnumbered), 1964 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Music 33 The Opéra-Comique pages 98-230, 1964 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Music 220 (301) Finals, 1947, 1948, 1954 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Music notes, 1947 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Samples of transcription (seminar to illustrate principles of editing), 1949-1950 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Class notes for Opera course (S-131 "Drama and Music in Opera"), Harvard, Summer 1955 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Music 302, 303, 304, 100, 1953-1958 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Music 376, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Music 110, 303, 304, 1958 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Lecture Notes Part I, c. 1962-1965 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Lecture Notes Part II, c. 1962-1965 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Lecture Notes Part III, c. 1962-1965 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Lecture Notes Part IV, c. 1962-1965 (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Music 684, c. 1964-1965 (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Music 483, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Abstracts of dissertations, books, etc., n.d. (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - Ambros V, 1950 (Box 50, Folder 17)
  - Bach chorale index by Warren E. Traub, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - Besseler, The Burgundian Epoch, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 19)
  - Barbara Lee (and others), n.d. (Box 50, Folder 20)
  - France (and other), n.d. (Box 50, Folder 21)
  - Gafurius, De harmonica, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 22)
  - Josquin, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 23)
  - Josquin, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 24)
  - Josquin des Prez memoranda, worksheets, Summer 1949 (Box 50, Folder 25)
  - Josquin, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 26)
  - "Some Observations on the Harmonic Practice of Josquin des Prez", 1949 (Box 50, Folder 27)
  - Notes on masses, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 28)
  - Discourse on Measured Music, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 29)
  - Memoranda and Proposals for Editorial Practice (seminar), 1949-1950 (Box 50, Folder 30)
  - "Missarum", n.d. (Box 50, Folder 31)
  - Musical Scales E.V. Huntington, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 32)
  - Musical Style of Lully, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 33)
  - Music mss. - various masses, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 34)
  - Notes for 16th century book, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 35)
  - Problems in Editing Early 19th Century Music, 1950 (Box 50, Folder 36)
  - 16th century theorists, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 37)
  - 16th century plainsong, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 38)
  - Mss. and prints seen in Italian libraries, October 1951 (Box 50, Folder 39)
  - Vol II, Mss. and prints seen in Italian libraries, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 40)
  - Vienna, 1951 (Box 50, Folder 41)
  - Wagner notes, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 43)
- Series VI. Norton Historical Anthology of Music (NOHAM), edited by Claude V. Palisca
  - First draft, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Revised edition 3 of History of Western Music, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - Contents, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Music examples, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - List #4, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - Plain chant mass, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - Medieval, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - Renaissance, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - Baroque, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - Classic, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - Modern, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - Add to Renaissance, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 34)
  - Add to Baroque, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 35)
  - Add to Baroque, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 36)
- Series VII. Photographs
  - Short History of Opera
    - Photographs of stage setting, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Negatives of folder 1, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Photographs of illustrations for revised edition, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Negatives of folder 3, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Negatives of folder 3, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Photograph from Paris Conservatoire, 1961 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Photographs from Paris Bibliothèque nationale, July 1961 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Photographs from Theater Museum München, January 1961 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Mademoiselle Boshot - Bibliothèque de l'opéra, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Photographs from Baroque sketches in the Drottningholm Theatre Museum, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Photographs from Vienna (postcards), 1961 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Film from Vienna, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Photographs from Vienna, 1961 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Photographs from Prof. Hellmuth Christian Wolff, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - Letters in relation to folder 14, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - Postcards, booklets from Drottningholmsteatern, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - Slides from Drottningholmsteatern, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - Photographs from Munich Theatermuseum, 1961 (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - Negatives with note, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 19)
    - Photographs with letter from Vienna, 1961 (Box 44, Folder 20)
    - Chaliapin as Boris, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 21)
    - Portraits of 18th-19th century opera composers, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 22)
    - Photographs from Dr. Heinz Becker, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 23)
    - Negatives of 18th-19th century opera composers, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 24)
    - Film from Dr. Heinz Becker, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 25)
  - Scarlatti operas
    - Alessandro Scarlatti: An Introduction to His Operas, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 26)
    - Uno Sposalizio(Griselda di Boccaccio) photograph, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 27)
    - Tracings and photographs of watermarks in Griselda, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 28)
    - München (Bayr. Stb.) 144 - Statira (transparencies of watermark and coat-of-arms), n.d. (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - Other photographs
    - Arcangelus Corellius - photograph and negative, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 29)
    - Slides for lecture: Symbol and Sound in Music (see 24-26), n.d. (Box 44, Folder 30)
    - Maps of the Netherlands, December 1960 (Box 44, Folder 31)
    - Negative of an opera theatre, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 32)
    - Slides of party for D.J.G., n.d. (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Personal photos of Grout, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Photographs and transparencies of two Roman theatres, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Transparencies of Michigan lecture, November 1950 (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Glass slides of score excerpts, stage sets, and composer portraits (ranging in period from medieval to Baroque), n.d. (Box 82)
- Series VIII. Collected concert and opera programs
  - Programs, 1933 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Five programs marked from Fred Petty, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Seven programs marked "gift" or "not seen", n.d. (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - One program, Warsaw, Poland, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Five programs, Netherlands, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Two programs, United States, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - One program, Salzburg Festpiele, 1960 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Four programs, Bavarian Opera Company, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Eight programs, Köln Opera Company, 1 museum booklet, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - One program, Hamburg, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Twelve programs from Stuttgart opera companies, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Two programs, Düsseldorf, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - One program, Frankfurt am Main, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 13)
- Series IX. Wire and tape recordings (wr. and tr.)
  - Schumann - Piano Quartet in Eb Major, Op. 44, 1950 (Box 47, Folder tr.)
  - Rehearsal of Bach works, n.d. (Box 47, Folder wr.)
  - Rehearsal of chorus a capella, n.d. (Box 47, Folder wr.)
  - Music for Archne, Richard Grayson, 1964 (Box 47, Folder tr.)
  - Holograph I, Earle Brown, 1959 (Box 47, Folder tr.)
  - Illustrations - 20th century opera (leftovers), 1963 (Box 47, Folder tr.)
  - Mozart - Don Giovanni, 1970 (Box 47, Folder tr.)
  - Some Aspects of American Music from the Beginning to 1915, Lecture, 1966 (Box 47, Folder tr.)
  - Tape recording of Grout's memorial service (TR-9901), April 26, 1987 (Box 47, Folder tr.)
- Series X. PhD. Dissertation, "The Origins of the Opèra Comique"
  - "The Origins of the Opera Comique" (photocopy), 2 bd. vols., 1939 (Box 48)
- Series XI. Inventories of Grout's Score Collection and Miscellaneous Scores and Parts
  - Films M1-M50 (notebook [microfilms list]), n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1-3)
  - Films M53-M150 (notebook [microfilms list]), n.d. (Box 58, Folder 4-5)
  - Films M151-M266 (notebook [microfilms list]), n.d. (Box 58, Folder 6-7)
  - Films ML1-ML34 (notebook [microfilms list]), n.d. (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Films ML35-ML69 (notebook [microfilms list]), n.d. (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Collections of Works by Various Composers (list), n.d. (Box 58, Folder 10-11)
  - Grout Project: ML44-ML45, M1-M139 (not complete sequence), n.d. (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Provisional catalogue of Scarlatti material given by Grout to Cornell, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 13)
  - Miscellany from small notebook, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Venice (Bibl. Marc.) - Cavalli, Pompeo Magno, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - Rome (Bibl. Apostolica, Vatican), Ms Chigi C VIII 234 - Ockeghem, Missa Ecce Ancilla Domini, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Rome (Bibl. Apostolica, Vatican), Cappela Sistina 23 - Josquin, Missa Gaudeamus: Kyrie, Gloria (first part), n.d. (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Josquin, Masses, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Josquin, Masses, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Unidentified big band jazz arrangement (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Misc. scores and parts I (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Misc. scores and parts II (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Misc. piano scores I, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Misc. piano scores II, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - Misc. piano scores III, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Misc. piano scores IV, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 6)